现在我们要实际创建这些节点。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Now we wanna
actually create these nodes.
为此，我们将侦听创建的任何 MDX 节点，并且
And to do that we're going to listen for
any MDX node that gets created, and
然后我们用它创建一个 docs 页面节点。
then we'll create a docs
page node out of it.
为了做到这一点，我们将添加另一个 API 钩子
So to do that,
we're going to add another API hook, and
这个叫做 onCreateNode。
this one is called onCreateNode.
这个给了我们一堆数据。
And this one gives us a bunch of data.
第一个要给我们的是创建的节点。
So the first thing that's gonna give
us is the node that was created.
它会给我们一个物体
It'll give us an object for
我们能做的就是帮助我们处理这个节点。
the actions that we can do that will
help us kinda process this node.
它将使我们能够加载给定节点的内容。
It will give us the ability to
load the content of a given node.
所以如果我们想把它交给父母，或者如果它有孩子，我们可以得到这些
So if we wanna get it to parent or
if it had children, we could get those and
它会给我们一个帮助器来创建一个节点 ID。
it'll give us a helper
to create a node ID.
最后，它会给我们提供选择。
And finally, it'll give us options.
所以在这里面,
So inside of this,
我们先从我们需要的选择开始。
we are going to start by getting
out just the options that we need.
所以我们要在这里使用基本路径，因为我们要设置路径
So we wanna use the base path in here,
because we're going to set the path for
文档页面，如果需要的话，它会包含基本路径,
the docs page to be, it's going to
include that base path if necessary,
因为这是它以后构建页面的方法，使用这条路径。
cuz this is how it will actually build
the pages later, using this path.
所以我们要拉出基本路径，我们将使用默认值。
So we're gonna pull the base path out and
we'll use the defaults.
好的，然后我们加载父节点。
Okay, and
then we're gonna load the parent node.
因此，当我们获得 MDX 节点时，MDX 节点是从文件节点生成的。
So when we get an MDX node, that MDX
node is generated off of a file node.
所以 Gatsby 的工作方式是 Gatsby 源文件系统创建文件节点。
So the way that Gatsby works is the Gatsby
source file system creates file nodes.
然后 Gatsby 插件 MDX 实际上是一个变压器插件。
And then Gatsby plugin MDX is
actually a transformer plugin.
它所做的就是寻找任何文件节点。
So what it's doing is it's looking for
any file nodes.
然后它检查实际使用这个 onCreateNode 的类型
And then it checks the type
actually using this onCreateNode
我们现在看到的 API。
API that we're looking at right now.
如果找到兼容的类型，在本例中是带 mdx 的文件
And if it finds compatible types, which
in this case would be files with a mdx
扩展名时，它将为名为子 MDX 的文件创建一个子节点。
extension, it will then create a child
node for the file called child MDX.
这就是我们在这里接收到的，是孩子 MDX。
And that is what we are receiving
here is the child MDX.
所以，我们要加载这个文件，这样我们就可以检查这个名字。
So, we wanna load that file so
that we can check that name.
记住，我们将文件名设置为盖茨比主题文档。
Remember, we set the name for
the files to Gatsby themed docs.
这是因为我们只想创建文档页面
And that's because we only
want to create docs pages for
这个主题下载的文档。
docs that are loaded by this theme.
我们不想把博客或其他东西变成文档页面。
We don't want to turn blogs or
anything else into docs pages.
所以我们要获取节点，也就是 node.parent。
So we're going to get the node,
which is the node.parent.
然后我们要确保我们
And then we wanna make sure that we
只能处理由这个东西加载的 MDX 文件。
only work on MDX files that
were loaded by this thing.
为此，我们设置了一个 if 语句。
And to do that we set up an if statement.
我们首先要检查的是这个节点的实际类型是 MDX。
And the first thing we're gonna check is
that the actual type of this node is MDX.
在《了不起的盖茨比》中，内部只是某个给定节点的元数据,
And in Gatsby, the internal is just
kind of metadata about a given node,
和 node.internal.type 将会反映
and the node.internal.type
is going to reflect
不管插件告诉它什么数据类型。
whatever the plugin told
it the data type was.
因此，如果是一个文件，内部类型将是 file。
So if it's a file,
the internal type would be file.
如果是 Mdx，Mdx 使用这个大写 m 小写 dx 作为文件类型。
If it's Mdx, Mdx uses this capital
M lowercase dx as its file type.
我们将使用文档页面作为文件类型。
We're gonna be using docs
page as our file type.
所以我们可以检查然后说，嘿，我只想处理 Mdx 文件或者
So we can just check and say, hey,
I only wanna work on Mdx files or
节点，所以如果我们没有任何保释。
Mdx nodes, so
if we don't have any bail out.
另一件我要检查的事情是父源实例
And then the other thing that I wanna
check is if the parent source instance
名字实际上不是盖茨比主题文档。
name is not actually Gatsby theme docs.
再说一次，我本不该这么做的。
And again, I should have made this not.
所以我们要做的就是提前回报。
So what we're doing is we're
doing an early return.
所以我们要说的是，如果节点类型不是 Mdx，或者
So what we’re saying is,
if the node type is not Mdx, or
文件 gatsby-theme-docs 的源实例名。
the source instance name of
the file gatsby-theme-docs.
源实例名称来自这里。
That source instance name comes from here.
所以不管我们在盖茨比源文件系统中设置的名称是什么,
So whatever we set as the name
in Gatsby source file system,
它将成为文件节点上的源实例名。
that will become the source
instance name on the file node.
因此，当我们加载父节点时，父节点是一个文件节点，我们可以检查
So when we load that parent, the parent
is a file node, and we can check
确保它是由我们的主题加载的，而不是其他文件。
to make sure that it was loaded by
our theme, and not some other file.
所以如果这些事情不是真的，我们就要退出。
So if those things aren't true,
we're gonna bail out.
但是一旦我们到了这里,
But once we get to here,
我们知道我们的节点是由我们的主题加载的 Mdx 节点。
we know that our node is an Mdx
node that was loaded by our theme.
这意味着我们可以开始定制它。
So that means we can
start to customize it.
所以我要做的第一件事就是确保如果我们有一个索引
So the first thing I'm going to do is I
wanna make sure that if we have an index
文件，我们要处理一个索引点 MDX,
file, we wanna treat
an index index dot MDX,
同样的方式，我们会一个索引点 HTML。
the same way that we
would an index dot HTML.
这意味着我们希望在文档中加载它
And what that means is we
want it to load up at docs
而不是文档索引，这将是默认的行为。
Instead of docs index,
which would be the default behavior.
所以我们要设置一个页面名称。
So we're gonna set up a page name.
我们将使用的页面名称是
And the page name that
we'll use is if the parent
Name 不是 index，我们将使用 parent.name。
name is not index,
we will use the parent.name.
如果是索引，我们就不填。
And if it is index we'll leave it blank.
这样，它就只是内容或基本路径。
In that way it would just be
the content or the base path.
因此，如果我们去 / docs 并且有一个索引
So if we go /docs and
have an index .Mdx there will be /docs and
这就是网址。
that will be the URL.
如果我们有一个 about. Mdx，它将是 / docs 和 / about。
And if we have an about.Mdx
it will be /docs and /about.
因为 parent.name 是没有扩展名的文件名。
Because the parent.name is the file
name without an extension.
所以我们有我们的页面名称，从那里我将继续和
So we have our page name and
from there I'm gonna go ahead and
使用创建节点操作，并接受一个对象，这是我们的新节点。
use the create node action and that
accepts an objects which is our new node.
所以我要做的第一件事就是创建一个节点 ID。
So the first thing I wanna
do is create a node ID.
并且节点 ID 可以是任意的，它只需要是唯一的。
And the node ID can be arbitrary,
it just needs to be unique.
所以我通常要做的就是把我们将要使用的类型
So what I typically do is I take
the type that we're going to use, and
然后获取现有节点 ID，并将其传递到 create node ID。
then I take the existing nodes ID,
and pass that into create node ID.
这将创建一个独特的散列。
And that'll create a unique hash.
所以这个想法是独一无二的，但是
So the the idea is already unique, but
然后把我们的类型添加进去，就得到了一个新的但也是唯一的散列。
then by adding our type to it,
we get a new but also unique hash.
一旦我有了 ID，我就可以添加标题。
Once I've got the ID,
I can add in the title.
所以题目会从前面的问题中显现出来。
And so the title is gonna
come out of the front matter.
但是如果没有设置，我们可以退回到文件名。
But if that's not set,
we can just fall back to the file name.
我们要检查更新的时间幸运的是,
We're gonna check the updated time and
fortunately,
盖茨比的文件系统会给我们提供这个，所以我们将使用父母修改时间。
Gatsby's file system will just give us
that, so we'll do parent modified time.
这是最后一次修改这个文件，所以非常好用。
And that's the last time that that file
was modified, so that's nice and handy.
然后，我想得到的路径，我要使用的路径模块。
Then, I wanna get the path and
I'm gonna use the path module.
确保我已经把它包含在这里了，我做到了。
Make sure I've got that included up here,
I do.
所以我要使用 path.join，我总是想以一个斜杠开头
So I'm gonna use path.join and I always
wanna start with a leading slash so
我们会把它写进去的。
we'll include that in there.
然后我会用棒道。
Then I'm gonna use the basepath.
然后我要使用父目录的相对目录。
And then I'm gonna use the relative
directory of the parent.
这意味着我们的医生,
And what that means is like in our docs,
我们可以建立 / 文档 / 反应 / 挂钩。
we could set up /docs/react/hooks.
国家管理或什么的
State management or something, and
Url 将反映内容路径中的目录结构。
the URL will reflect the directory
structure inside of our content path.
因此，对于管理内容的人来说，这更符合逻辑。
So that makes it a little more logical for
people who are managing content.
无论文件夹结构在内容中是什么样子
Whatever the folder structure
looks like in the content
会反映在网址和网站的层次结构中。
will be what gets reflected on the URL and
in the hierarchy of the site.
一旦你有了这个相对目录,
And once you've got that
relative directory in there,
我们会加上页名，哎呀。
we will include the page name, whoops.
跳到文件夹的开头，页面名称。
Skip to the beginning of the folder,
page name.
所以这是我们现在唯一的崩溃。
So this now is our only collapse out.
所以我们可以看到整个过程。
So we can see the whole thing.
所以我们的路径将从斜杠开始。
So our path then is going to be
starting at the leading slash.
如果我们有一个类似 / docs 的基本路径,
If we have a base path like /docs,
然后相对目录，以匹配文件层次结构。
then the relative directory
to match the file hierarchy.
然后是页面名称，如果它的索引是空的或者是文件名。
And then the page name which will either
be the filename or empty if its index.
那么，这说得通吗？
So, does this make sense?
在我们继续前进之前，有人对此有什么问题吗？
Does anybody have questions about
how this works before we move on?
演讲者2: 我想澄清一下，我们这么做的目的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So I guess just to clarify,
the purpose of what we're doing
这里是创建知道我们可以查询和 GraphQL。
here is creating knows that
we can query and GraphQL.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 没错。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Exactly.
讲者2: 好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 是的，所以
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Yeah, so
我们要做的就是在这里定义这个文档页面。
what we're doing is we're basically
saying we define this docs page up here.
标题路径更新。
Id titled path updated.
在 onCreateNode 中，id 标题路径更新了，我们创建了所有这些文件。
And in onCreateNode, id title path
updated, we're creating all these files.